<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Marks Blog</title><link>/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Marks Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>When 'Buzzwords' Reveal an Interview Leveling Mismatch</title><link>/posts/when-buzzwords-arent-buzzwords/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/when-buzzwords-arent-buzzwords/</guid><description>&lt;p>I recently interviewed for a senior engineering role at a well-known fintech company. The interview went sideways in an interesting way, and the feedback I received reveals something important about how technical interviews can fail when leveling expectations aren&amp;rsquo;t aligned.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-interview">The Interview&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The system design question was straightforward: &lt;strong>&amp;ldquo;Design a system that displays the top 5 songs currently being played in real-time across our streaming platform.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I proposed a solution using:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Practical GitOps Pattern</title><link>/posts/gitops/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 19:02:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/gitops/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Introduction&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
If you’ve spent any time working with Kubernetes, you’ve probably heard of &lt;em>GitOps&lt;/em> -a methodology that treats Git as the source of truth for defining and operating infrastructure and applications. In this post, I’ll walk you through a GitOps setup that uses a hierarchical folder structure, combining Helm, Helmfile, and Kustomize to give you robust, testable, and scalable deployments. We’ll also see how tools like Flux and Tilt fit into the workflow, enabling both automated deployments and seamless local development.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>GitOps PR Diffs: Review What You Deploy</title><link>/posts/gitops-pr-diffs/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/gitops-pr-diffs/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Introduction&lt;/strong>
A common pattern I see promoted is using tools that show you what will change in your cluster &lt;em>at sync time&lt;/em> - after your code is already merged. In my view, this is already too late and goes against GitOps principles. How can Git be the source of truth if there are extra steps between merge and understanding impact?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll show you how to generate manifest diffs &lt;em>during PR review&lt;/em>, so reviewers see exactly what will change in the cluster before they approve.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using socat to backdoor via kubernetes</title><link>/posts/socat/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 09:02:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/socat/</guid><description>&lt;p>Sometimes when you&amp;rsquo;re developing or debugging locally you need access to resources that are exposed to your cluster.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Typically, most organisations use VPN&amp;rsquo;s to enable you to access these resources, but there&amp;rsquo;s a much easier way.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="socat">Socat.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The alpine/socat image is perfect for enabling backdoor access to private or internal services that are available to
your cluster without having to set up and manage VPN&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>How it works is pretty simple. We run a socat pod exposing a service that&amp;rsquo;s viewable by the pod but not by us.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>